Owen Senowitz

Seeking a Software Engineering position to utilize my skills as a developer. I've been developing applications and working with databases since 2014 using languages such as Java, Python, C#, C++, JavaScript. I've applied those languages to build API's, web front ends and relational databases.

104 Copper Hill Dr.
Cary NC, 27518
(919) 632-6259
owen-senowitz.com
owen.senowitz@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Lowe's, Charlotte NC— Software Engineer Intern

MAY 2022 - AUGUST 2022

I was an intern of a team that handled 600+ million API requests per day. I used Java Spring Boot, Kafka, Couchbase and PostgreSQL to supply our customers with accurate pricing information.

East Carolina University, Greenville NC — Assistant Software Engineer

SEPTEMBER 2021- MAY 2022

Worked on developing Identity Server 4 applications using C# and JavaScript. We use scrum as our agile methodology, with daily standups where we discuss what we did yesterday, what we are doing today and any blockers that we have.

Chick-Fil-A, Cary NC — Team Member

MAY 2018 - JULY 2019

Worked as a frontline cashier ringing up customer orders on our POS system. Worked in the kitchen preparing customers food and led in training of new employees.

Arma 3 Altis Life Server, Cary NC — Owner

SEPTEMBER 2014 - JANUARY 2016

Wrote SQF scripts for a community of over 100 concurrent players. Worked closely with administrators and moderators to troubleshoot server issues. Used AWS EC2 instances to host the game server and Used AWS MySQL database to support my AWS environment through donations via the players on my servers.

FRONT-END SKILLS

HTML

JavaScript

Bootstrap

React

CSS

SCSS

BACK-END SKILLS

Java

Spring Boot

Python

C#

C++

Kafka

MySQL

PostgreSQL

Couchbase

LANGUAGES

English

EDUCATION

East Carolina University, Greenville NC — Computer Science

August 2019 - PRESENT